KELECHI OLEKA

Frontend Developer || Lekki, Lagos Nigeria

PROFILE

An I.T professional with 4 + years of experience in Fullstack web development, I have developed a strong proficiency in UI/UX design and implementing complex web applications. My expertise and soft skills makes me a valuable asset to any team. I wish to secure a role that offers the opportunity to showcase my technical prowess, thereby making a meaningful contribution to the growth and success of the company.

FUNCTIONAL PROJECTS:

Havenlinks Rental Marketplace - Demo | GitHub

Technologies used: Html, Javascript, Bootstrap, Php, Laravel, Stripe, SQL

A Userfriendly, multi vendor rental marketplace that enables customers to easily search, manage, List and book rental properties of any kind,seamlessly

By working on this project, I have gained valuable experience in payment gateway implementation using Stripe, project management, and customer service

WORKING EXPERIENCE:

Aeries Solutions | Remote | Front-end Developer

Reference: Mrs Salome Dede | +2348033362166 | Email:

Contact@aeriescommunity.com

[April 2022 - Present]

- Regular collaborations with the back-end team to Implement web Solutions, micro services as well write clean reusable codes.
- Optimized website loading speed by hosting and managing media files on a CDN
- Successful quality testing of applications to ensure responsiveness and efficiency before deployment.

JOBITECH | Ondo State, Nigeria | Web Development Instructor

Reference: Miss Blessing Chima | +234 701 247 6443 | Email:

bchima1017@gmail.com

[February 2022 - December 2022]

- Successfully taught advanced web development concepts like
 Object Oriented Programming in Python and JavaScript to Youths aged 17 - 25 years.
- Mentored classes of about 20 students and used technologies like ChatGPT to improve the learning process.
- Helped to improve outdated Full-stack development teaching

CONTACT DETAILS

+2347049563046
Olekakelechi4u@gmail.com
LinkedIn
GitHub
Personal Portfolio

FUNCTIONAL SKILLS

Next Js, React Js, Redux, TypeScript, MongoDB, GraphQL, Express, Node Js, Object oriented programming, Rest API, SQL, OpenAI, practical knowledge of c# and python, UI/UX Design

TOOLS:

Git/GitHub, Docker Digital Ocean, React-Bricks, Sanity CMS, Photoshop, Illustrator, Canva, Microsoft Office, Figma

Other Skills:

Multitasking, Organizational skills, Data Entry & Analytics, Power Bi, Tableau, Quick Learner Good Communicator

Languages:

English

Retro-Recycled | Remote | Social Media Content Specialist

Site: https://linktr.ee/retrorecycled

[November 2022 - Present]

- Collaborated with team members to design an effective Social media strategy
- Designed the brand logo using illustrator
- Designed a custom Linktree using html, javascript and css and Video content editing using Adobe premiere pro CC

SD Worx | Ebene, Mauritius | Functional Analyst

Reference: Mr Collins Mahony | +230 5858 5690

[2018 - December 2021]

- Tasked with translating business requirements into clear functional requirements for the developers
- Worked closely together with the product owner; UX/UI designers and the development team
- Analyze reported bugs and carry-out the first troubleshooting

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

ALX - Software Engineering (in view)

Udemy- Python Programming Machine Learning (Advanced) 2023

NYSC - Certificate of National Service 2022

Middlesex University Mauritius - B.sc Information Technology 2020

NIIT - HONORS DIPLOMA IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (SOFTWARE

ENGINEERING) 2018